不正視聴!?
(カカシ)土遁 土流壁！
Earth Style: Mud Wall!
雷切！
Lightning Blade!
《なんだ 今のは？》
What was that?!
(天道)コピー忍者の はたけカカシ。
会えて光栄だ。
Hatake Kakashi the Copy Ninja...
I'm honored to meet you.
九尾は どこだ？
Where is the Nine-Tails?
それは 愚問でしょ？
That... is a silly question.
うわあ!!
what did I really lose that day?
ano hi honto ni ushinatta monotte nan dattakke
for the life of me I can't remember
tou ni wasureteshimatta yo
we slowly lost sight of each other in the twilight
yuugure de futari sukoshizutsu mienakunatteitte
and yet we're stuck here unable to go home
sore nanoni bokura kaerezu ni ita
weak, frail souls lost in the world
dokoka ni kowaresou na moroi kokoro
we act strong to hide their fragility
tsuyogaru kotoba de ootte kakushiteru
(チョウザ)あそこか。
hide their fragility
ootte kakushiteru
(チョウジ)父ちゃん！
ボクも一緒に。
うん。
so farewell, but even forced apart
sayonara aenakunattatte
our stories go on
bokura wa tsuzuki ga aru kara
even in a world without you, I run
kimi no inai sekai datte hashiru yo
to someday get past the pain
itsuka no itami mo koete
Pain vs Kakashi
Over there!
Pa!
I'm coming too!
いくぞ！
Let's go!
《なんだ 今の術は？
What was that jutsu just now?
衝撃波の感覚とは違う。
It felt different from a shock wave...
ヤツを中心に 辺りがすべて
吹き飛ばされている》
Everything around him
was blasted away,
with him as the epicenter.
《なら…。
Then...
これならどうする!?》
How will you counter this?
《物理攻撃
忍術までも弾き返すのか？
Not just physical attacks...
He can repel Ninjutsu as well?!
なんてヤツだ。
Impressive.
さあて どうやって…》
Now then, how should I...?
もう一人か！
Another one?
《もらった！》
You're mine!
《うっ コイツ 前を向いたままで！》
This guy...
He was facing directly ahead, yet...
《そうか》
I see...
((フカサク : ヤツらの目は リンクしとる。
Their eyes are linked!
視野がつながっとって
共有しとるんじゃ。
Their field of vision is
connected and shared.
ペインを相手にするときは
一対一にもっていくのが➡
When you face Pain,
you must only fight them one-on-one.
基本戦術になるけん。 覚えとけ。
Remember this well.
ヤツらは 一個体につき
１系統の能力しか使えん。
Each of them can use
only one type of skill.
(その能力を見極めるのが
肝心じゃ))
Deducing those skills will be crucial.
《こんなヤツを６人も
相手にしてたのか 自来也様は。
Lord Jiraiya took on
six of them at once?!
まともじゃないね どうも》
I must say... That's crazy...
あっ！
うわっ！
《そうか！ コイツの能力は…》
I get it! That's his ability!
Pain...
《ペイン コイツを相手に
１人で戦っても勝機はない！
I have no chance
if I fight them alone.
仲間に増援の連絡。
コイツの能力も伝えなきゃな。
I must call for reinforcements,
and let them know
what this one's ability is!
この体で できるとこまで…》
I have to do as much as
my body can handle!
《うっ！ しまっ！》
Damn...
うっ!!
《雷遁影分身！》
A Lightning Style Shadow Clone!
これで 一匹はやれたな。
なぁ カカシ！
One down...
Right, Kakashi?
こっちも
準備はしてたんですけどね。
Actually, I was all set too.
チャクラの温存できて
助かりました。
But this will help me preserve
some chakra.
Thank you.
(チョウザ)大丈夫なのか？
Are you all right?
Yes... Well... I'll manage.
えぇ まぁ どうにか。
トラップ影分身…。
A Trap Shadow Clone...
He had already planted it back then.
あのとき すでに…。
《チョウザ : 相手の能力がなんなのかを
判断するまで➡
Until he can confirm
an opponent's abilities,
変わり身と分身を使う
カカシの常套手段。
Kakashi always uses Substitute
and Shadow Clone Jutsu.
前 組んだときと
変わってねえな。
Hasn't changed since
the last time we teamed up.
相変わらず 巧みなやり方だ。
Skilled as always.
だとすると…》
Which means...
チャクラ量は大丈夫か？
Do you have enough chakra?
もう 雷遁影分身
使っちゃったんで➡
I've already used my Lightning Style
Shadow Clone
チャクラ 半分以上
持っていかれてます。
and exhausted over
half my chakra.
これほどの相手に 長期戦は
キツイってのが正直なところ。
To be honest, a drawn-out battle against
a formidable opponent like him
is going to be difficult for me.
ですが ヤツの能力は
少しだけ見抜けました。
However, I've figured out
a little of his abilities.
Pa, he's coming!
父ちゃん 来たよ！
神羅天征！
Almighty Push...
クソッ！
There!
あれは…。
That's...
何をしたんだ？ ヤツは。
What did he just do?
すべての攻撃を
弾いたんです。
He repelled all our attacks.
ヤツの術は 己を中心に
物質を引き寄せたり➡
Using himself as the epicenter,
his jutsu allows him to pull in
or push objects away.
突き放したりするもののようです。
Similar to the magnetic laws
of attraction and repulsion...
いわば
引力と斥力のようなものかと。
ただし 連続では
その術も使用できないようで➡
However, it seems he cannot
utilize that jutsu consecutively.
I know for certain that
there is an interval of time
次の術を発動するまでには➡
before he can activate
the next jutsu.
少しの間 インターバルがあるのは確か。
さっきので
みんな やられちゃったよ。
Everyone else has been taken down!
全部 攻撃が弾かれるのに
どうやって やっつけるの？
If he can repel all attacks,
how do we defeat him?
術のインターバルも短いようだしな。
近づけんぞ！
The interval between jutsu
seems short too.
We can't get close.
しかし そこを狙うしか
ありませんね。
However, that's our only chance.
少し 考えがあります。
I have an idea.
協力してください。
And I need your help.
なかなか いい動きをする。
You move quite well...
術も多彩だ。
And you have a wide range of jutsu.
お前のようなヤツは
殺しておかなければ➡
People like you need to be killed,
or you may pose
a problem later.
のちのち厄介になる。
《今です》
Now!
- Double...
- Human...
ダブル肉弾戦車！
- Boulder!
Too slow...
遅い！
《はたけカカシ。
地面からの攻撃前に➡
Hatake Kakashi!
He planted this chain underground
before attacking from below!
この鎖を
地中へ仕込んでいたのか…》
Lightning Blade!
雷切！
《いけ カカシ先生！》
Go, Kakashi-sensei!
Finish him, Kakashi!
《決めろ カカシ！》
The other Pain!
He could still move?!
《もう１人のペイン…
まだ動けたのか？》
Make it in time!
《間に合え！》
動けないフリ➡
Your inability to move...
doesn't seem faked.
では なさそうだな？
《遅かったか…》
I didn't make it...
I know that you're not
a Shadow Clone.
お前が影分身でないことは
わかっている。
確実に死んでもらう。
I shall make certain of your death...
It's over.
終わりだ。
念には念だ。
うかつには近づくまい。
But just to be safe...
I will not approach you.
Humph... Know pain.
フッ… 痛みを知れ！
《綱手 : ここまでの被害とは…》
The damage is devastating...
いけません。
みなさん 急ぎましょう。
No...
Everyone, let us hurry!
早く！ 急ぎましょう。
ええ わかりました。
- Yes!
- Let us hurry. Let us hurry.
Now, hurry.
《父ちゃん…。
Pa...
カカシ先生！》
Kakashi-sensei!
(サクラ)これで応急処置は終わりよ。
I'm done with first-aid treatment.
あとは添え木をお願い。
はい。
Please finish with the splint.
(イルカ)サクラ！
Right...
Sakura!
(イルカ)負傷者 もう１名だ。 頼む！
One more wounded! Hurry!
わかりました。
そちらに寝かせてください。
All right.
Please lay him down there.
父ちゃん…。
Pa...
ボクをかばって。
You tried to protect me...
(カカシ)泣くのはあとだ チョウジ。
Save the crying for later... Choji...
まだ動けるなら ペインの能力を
綱手様へ報告してくれ。
If... you are able to move...
report to Tsunade-sama
about Pain's abilities.
すぐに対策を立てるんだ。
A counter strategy is imperative!
カ… カカシ先生。
K-Kakashi... Sensei?
リアクションはあとだ。
それより早く… 走れ！
Reflect later!
You must... hurry!
Run!
でも ボク… ボク！
But... I... I...
チョウザさんの犠牲を ムダにするな！
Don't let Choza's sacrifice
be in vain!
しつこい ヤツらだ。
Persistent fellows, aren't you?
クソッ まだ！
Damn it... He's still...!
《狙いは チョウジか！》
He's after Choji!
ひっ… とっ！
Pa...!
《父ちゃん 今まで ありがとう》
Pa... Thank you for everything
you've done.
見ててくれ！
Just you watch!
走れ チョウジ！
Run! Choji!
うお～っ！
《おそらく今のチャクラでは
ヤツの体全体は無理だ。
I daresay with the chakra I have left
it's impossible to destroy
his entire body.
それに もう一度 使えば➡
And... if I use it one more time,
すべてのスタミナとチャクラを
使い切ることになる。
I'll exhaust all my stamina
and chakra.
オレの命は…》
My life will be...
《カカシ : 生きている者に
この情報を託すこと。
To entrust this piece of information
to those who still live.
それが 木ノ葉を救うため
今のオレがとれる最善の方法》
This is the best method I have
right now to save the Hidden Leaf!
そうか！
I get it...
あれも その瞳術で
やりすごしていたというわけか。
So... he also... got by...
with that Ocular Jutsu...
《ま どうやら オレも
ここまでのようだよ。
Well... it seems this is it
for me, too.
オビト… リン…》
Obito... Rin...
((オビト : 里のヤツらが何と言おうと
お前は立派な上忍だ。
Whatever the village may say...
You are a great jonin.
オレは もう死ぬ。
けど お前の目になって➡
I'm about to die...
But... I'll become your eyes
and see the future for you.
これから先を見てやるからよ。
(リンを頼むぜ…))
Take care of Rin...
オビト…。
Obito...
《お前の目になって
先を見据えるのは➡
Seems this is
as far as it goes...
for me to see the future
as your eyes.
どうやら ここまでのようだ》
《リンを守れなかったオレだ。
I wasn't able to protect Rin...
お前との約束を
破ってばっかりだが➡
I keep breaking my promises
to you.
許してくれ。
Forgive me.
オビト リン 先生…》
Obito...
Rin... Sensei...
《オレも 今から そっちへ行くよ》
I'll... be joining you now.
カカシか？
フッ こんなところにいたんだ。
Is that you, Kakashi?
So this is where you were...
お前の話を聞かせてくれないか？
あぁ。
Will you tell me your story?
Sure... It's a really long story,
so I want to take my time.
すごく長くなるから
ゆっくり話したいんだけど。
あぁ いいさ。
Yeah... that's fine.
あのね… 父さん。
Well... Father...
どうなさったんですか？
Is something wrong?
(カツユ)綱手様！
Tsunade-sama!
あ あの…。
U-Um...
カツユは すでに
里の者たち ほぼすべてについた。
Katsuyu has already attached herself
to most of the people
of the village.
すまない 続きをやろう。
Sorry. Let us continue...
綱手様！
Tsunade-sama!
敵の１人の能力が割れました！
We cracked the ability of
one of our enemies!
うむ 聞こう。
Tell me.
性別は男
年齢は見るかぎり25～30。
He is male.
Between 25-30 years of age.
特徴は鼻に６つ
耳に７つのピアスをしています。
Distinguishing marks
are piercings,
six in his nose and seven
in his ears.
能力は
引力と斥力のような術を使用。
His ability is a jutsu that
simulates magnetic attraction
and repulsion.
己の狙ったものを
自分へと引きつけることが可能。
He can attract targeted objects
to himself.
そして 忍術のすべての攻撃を
弾くことができます。
And he can repel
every ninjutsu attack.
弾く？ すべてか？
Repel?! All of them?
はい。 ただし
その術を使用した場合➡
Yes! However, once he uses
either jutsu,
次の術を使用するまで
５秒ほどのインターバルが存在します。
there is a five-second interval.
たった５秒か。
Five seconds... That's all?
よく知らせてくれた。
これで犠牲は随分と減る。
You did well to report this!
Our sacrifices will
lessen considerably.
カツユを通し
情報をみんなに伝えるぞ！
Pass on this information to
everyone via Katsuyu!
(みんな)はっ！
チョウザ班は➡
- Yes, ma'am!
Team Choza provided back-up
for Kakashi-sensei
カカシ先生の援護。
２人の敵を相手に➡
against two of the enemies...
ボク以外は
ほぼ全滅したと思われます。
It is believed everyone
except myself perished.
チョウザのところへ行け。
Go back to Choza!
早く病院へ運ぶんだ。
Take him to the hospital
immediately!
He can still be saved.
Huh?!
Then... Pa is...
Yes...
Thank goodness! I'm so glad!
Kakashi...
What about Kakashi-sensei?!
Just hurry, Choji...
yesterday, I cut my hair a little
kinou sukoshi kami wo kitta
if I don't say it, I'm sure
iwanakareba kitto
nobody will realise, I guess
daremo kizukanai darou kedo
for a long time
nankagetsu ka bun no
I looked
watashi ga yuka ni
at what fell down on the floor
okkochita no wo mita
I closed my eyes
me wo tojite
and I could hear the sound of rain
kikoete kita ame no oto
even from above the clouds, I'm sure
kumo no ue demo kitto
take out a pair of scissors
hasami mochidashite
we're waiting for the light
hikari wo matteiru
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide koide
pedal, and come on
koideiku yo
right now, right now, right now, right now, right now
imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu
bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha
pedal
koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
Next Episode
今なら まだ助かる。
I was told each Pain could only use one skill.
え？ じゃあ 父ちゃんは…。
あぁ。
Then it's strange...
Jiraiya-sama defeated the Pain who can use Summoning Jutsu.
I saw her when reading through the Hidden Rain ninja's mind...
うぅ… よかった！
よかったよ！
But what's going on?! She was clearly a corpse!
Inoichi-san... Please tell me more in detail.
We will uncover his mystery together!
カカシ… カカシ先生は？
Mystery of Pain
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Mystery of Pain"
早く行け チョウジ。